<refentry id="hinotes">
   <refmeta>
      <refentrytitle>hinotes</refentrytitle>
      <manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
      <refmiscinfo>Copyright FSF 1996-2005</refmiscinfo>
   </refmeta>
   <refnamediv>
      <refname>hinotes</refname>
      <refpurpose>Syncronize your Hi-Notes database with your desktop
         machine.
      </refpurpose>
   </refnamediv>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Section</title>
      <para>pilot-link: Conduits</para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Synopsis</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>hinotes</emphasis>
         [<option>-p</option>|<option>--port</option> &lt;<userinput>port</userinput>&gt;]
         [<option>--version</option>] [<option>-q</option>|<option>--quiet</option>]
         [<option>-?</option>|<option>--help</option>] [<option>--usage</option>]
         [<option>-d</option>|<option>--dirname</option> <filename>dir</filename>]
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Description</title>
      <para>Hi-Notes must be installed on your Palm handheld (and at least one
         entry must exist within Hi-Notes).
      </para>
      <para>By default, the contents of your Palm's Hi-Notes database
         (Hi-NoteDB.pdb) will be written to STDOUT as a standard Unix mailbox
         (in mbox-format) file, with each memo as a separate message. The
         subject
         of each message will be set as the category.
      </para>
      <para>The memos will be written to STDOUT unless the
         <userinput>-d</userinput> option is specified.
         Using <userinput>-d</userinput> will be save the memos in
         subdirectories of
         <filename>dir</filename>.  Each subdirectory will contain the name of
         a	category on the Palm where the record was stored, and will contain
         the memos
         found in that category. 
      </para>
      <para>Each memo's filename will be the first
         line (up to the first 40 characters) of the memo.  Control characters,
         slashes, and equal signs that would otherwise appear in filenames are
         converted using the correct MIME's quoted-printable encoding.
      </para>
      <para>Please see http://www.cyclos.com/ for more information on Hi-Note.
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>warning</title>
      <para>Note that if you have two memos in the same category whose first
         lines
         are identical, one of them will be OVERWRITTEN! This is unavoidable at
         the present time, but may be fixed in a future release. Also, please
         note
         that syncronizing Hi-Note images is not supported at this time, only
         text.
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>options</title>
      <refsect2>
         <title>hinotes option</title>
         <para>
            <userinput>-d</userinput>
            <filename>dir</filename>
         </para>
         <blockquote>
            <para>Stores the Hi-Note entries in subdirectories of
               <filename>dir</filename>. Each subdirectory will contain the
               name of a
               category on the Palm where the record was stored, and will
               contain the
               memos found in that category.
            </para>
            <para>Each memo's filename will be the first line (up to the first
               40
               characters) of the memo. Control characters, slashes, and equal
               signs
               ('=') that would otherwise appear in filenames are converted
               using the
               correct MIME's quoted\-printable encoding methods.
            </para>
         </blockquote>
      </refsect2>
      <refsect2>
         <title>conduit options</title>
         <para>
            <option>-p</option>, <option>--port</option>
            &lt;<userinput>port</userinput>&gt;
         </para>
         <blockquote>
            <para>
               Use device file &lt;<filename>port</filename>&gt; to communicate
               with the Palm handheld. If this is not specified,
               <emphasis>hinotes</emphasis> will look for the
               <filename>$PILOTPORT</filename> environment variable. If neither
               are found, <emphasis>hinotes</emphasis> will print the usage
               information.
            </para>
         </blockquote>
         <para>
            <option>--version</option>
         </para>
         <blockquote>
            <para>Display the copyright information,version number, licence
               details
               and build details and exit without connecting.
            </para>
         </blockquote>
         <para>
            <option>-q</option>, <option>--quiet</option>
         </para>
         <blockquote>
            <para>Suppress 'Hit HotSync button' message</para>
         </blockquote>
      </refsect2>
      <refsect2>
         <title>Help options</title>
         <para>
            <option>-?</option>, <option>--help</option>
         </para>
         <blockquote>
            <para>Show the help message and exit without connecting.</para>
         </blockquote>
         <para>
            <option>--usage</option>
         </para>
         <blockquote>
            <para>Display a brief usage message and exit without connecting.</para>
         </blockquote>
      </refsect2>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Usage</title>
      <para>The program will dump your MemoPad database (MemoDB.pdb) from the
         Palm
         and output format suitable for the <filename>Hi-Notes</filename>
         application
         to use.
      </para>
      <para>
         Please see <filename>http://www.cyclos.com/</filename> for more
         information on Hi-Note.
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Author</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>hinotes</emphasis> was originally written by Kenneth
         Albanowski, based on code by Bill Goodman
         <email>bgoodman@cyclos.com</email> and modified by Michael Bravo
         <email>mbravo@kronverk.spb.su</email>
      </para>
      <para>This manual page was written by Neil Williams
         <email>linux@codehelp.co.uk</email>
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Reporting Bugs</title>
      <para>Report bugs at:
         <emphasis>http://bugs.pilot-link.org</emphasis>
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <para>This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
         modify it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as
         published by the Free Software Foundation; either version 2 of the 
         License,  or  (at your option) any later version.
      </para>
      <para>This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
         but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
         MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
         General Public License for more details.
      </para>
      <para>You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public
         License along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
         Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA 02111-1307 
         USA
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>See Also</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>pilot-link</emphasis>(7)
      </para>
   </refsect1>
</refentry>
