<refentry id="ietf2datebook">
   <refmeta>
      <refentrytitle>ietf2datebook</refentrytitle>
      <manvolnum>1</manvolnum>
      <refmiscinfo>Copyright FSF 1996-2005</refmiscinfo>
   </refmeta>
   <refnamediv>
      <refname>ietf2datebook</refname>
      <refpurpose>
         Converts IETF agenda format to <emphasis>install-datebook</emphasis> format
      </refpurpose>
   </refnamediv>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Section</title>
      <para>pilot-link: Tools</para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Synopsis</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>ietf2datebook</emphasis> &lt; ietf-agenda &gt; datebook.txt
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Description</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>ietf2datebook</emphasis> is a Perl script that converts IETF
         (<filename>http://www.ietf.org</filename>) agenda to format suitable for the
         <filename>install-datebook</filename> program. The agenda file is given to it as standard
         input and the output file is sent to standard output. Please remove all headers and
         footers from the agenda file before giving it to <emphasis>ietf2datebook</emphasis>.
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Options</title>
      <para>none</para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Usage</title>
      <para>
         The program will read IETF agenda from its stdin and output format suitable for the
         <emphasis>install-datebook</emphasis> program to STDOUT.
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Author</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>ietf2datebook</emphasis> was written by Tero Kivinen
         <email>kivinen@iki.fi</email>
      </para>
      <para>
         This manual page was converted to XML by Neil Williams <email>linux@codehelp.co.uk</email>
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Reporting Bugs</title>
      <para>
         Report bugs at: <emphasis>http://bugs.pilot-link.org</emphasis>
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>Copyright</title>
      <para>
         This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it under the terms of
         the GNU General Public License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
         version 2 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.
      </para>
      <para>
         This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY;
         without even the implied warranty of MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. 
         See the GNU General Public License for more details.
      </para>
      <para>
         You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License along with this program;
         if not, write to the Free Software Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston,
         MA 02111-1307 USA
      </para>
   </refsect1>
   <refsect1>
      <title>See Also</title>
      <para>
         <emphasis>read-ical</emphasis>(1),
         <emphasis>pilot-xfer</emphasis>(1),
         <emphasis>install-datebook</emphasis>(1),
         <emphasis>pilot-link</emphasis>(7).
      </para>
   </refsect1>
</refentry>
